so we have seen our function in line and
quiz now let's talk about its solution
after scheduling
how many cycles well let's see first
what the scheduling will do
we have a load we have to do it before
the call
and after the call we can do the store
so really scheduling can do nothing here
here we need to do the multiplication
and then the ad depends on it and then
we can only return so really there is
nothing scheduling can do here so really
we just need to figure out for this
sequence of instructions how many cycles
does it take to do it
one way of doing that would be to say
that the load begins in the first cycle
in the second cycle it's still going on
so we can use the result in the third
cycle in the second cycle however we can
do the call
the call also takes two cycles so we
really can execute this instruction in
cycle four
at that time a0 is available
the multiplication takes three cycles so
in cycles
four five and six the multiplication is
happening and only cycle 7 can we do
this because it's using the result of
this instruction
we can do the return
immediately afterwards
so return now is happening in cycles 8
and 9 and finally in cycle 10 we are
back here and then the store of course
takes only one cycle so really after 10
cycles we are done
now let us see what the inlining will do
what it will do is it will simply take
these two instructions and replace the
call with them now let's see
can we do some scheduling around it we
need to load a0
then we're going to use it in
multiplication then we're going to use
it in the addition and then we're going
to use the result of it in the store so
again scheduling is not going to help us
here however we have eliminated the call
and the return so now what happens is we
have
the load begins in cycle one next we
will try to do the multiplication but we
can only do it in cycle three because
the load needs to produce the value for
two cycles in cycles one and two before
we can use it next we have the
multiplication happening in cycles three
four and five so we can only do this in
cycle six the add only takes one cycle
and the store
can then happen in cycle seven and
that's when it finishes
so after inlining and scheduling we have
reduced this to seven cycles
mainly by eliminating the call and the
return